자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
안녕하세요?
How are you today?
찾는 게 있으십니까?
Do you see anything you like?
데니스 있습니까?
보통 데니스가 절 담당했거든요
Is Dennis here?
He usually takes care of me.
오, 아뇨
데니스는 관뒀습니다
Oh, no, I'm afraid Dennis quit.
관뒀다고요?
He quit?
네. 단골손님 한 분 때문에
무척 힘들어 하는 것 같더군요
Yeah, apparently he had one regular
customer that was driving him crazy.
그게 누굴까 궁금해 하느라
밤을 꼴딱 새게 생겼네요
Now, we're gonna be up
all night wondering who that was.
도와 드릴까요?
Can I help you?
데니스가 관뒀대요
Dennis quit.
네. 우린 딱 이런 셔츠를
찾고 있거든요
Yes, we're looking for
another shirt just like this.
- 같은 셔츠가 필요하세요?
- 똑같은 걸로요, 네
- You want the same shirt?
- Identical, yeah.
같은 칼라에 같은 무늬
목둘레 16인치에 팔 길이 33인치요
Same collar, same pattern,
16 inch neck, 33 inch sleeve.
좋습니다. 하지만 이미 그런 걸
하나 가지고 계시니까
Okay, but you already have
one of those.
변화를 좀 시도해 보셔도
좋을 것 같군요. 왜냐하면...
So, maybe it's time to try
a little variety, because...
아닌지도 모르겠네요
좋습니다
Or maybe not.
Okay.
네, 여기 있군요
Yeah, there you go.
목둘레 16인치
팔 길이 33인치입니다
16 inch collar, 33 inch sleeve.
아냐... 이건 6번이 검사한 거예요
6번은 별로 마음에 안 들던데
No, this one's inspected by number 6.
I'm not a big fan of number 6.
8번 검사원이 검사한 거 있나요?
Do you have any that are
inspected by number 8?
농담이시죠?
You're kidding, right?
아니시군요
좋습니다
You're not kidding.
Okay.
손님이 왕이죠
The customer's always right.
적어도 오늘이 오기 전까지는...
At least until today.
5번
Number 5.
2번
Number 2.
좋아요, 여기 있습니다
Okay, here you go.
8번이 검사한 거예요
Inspected by number 8.
- 정말 차이가 있나요?
- 농담하세요?
- Is there really a difference?
- Are you kidding?
이걸 보세요
Look at this.
봐요. 그분은 정말 예술가예요
Look, she's an artist.
그분을 안 지 수년이 됐는데요
Oh, I've been admiring
her work for years.
셔츠, 바늘땀, 단추 하나하나가
전부 완벽하거든요
You know, every shirt, every stitch,
every button is perfect.
터진 곳이...
터진 곳이 있어요
There's a tear.
- 어디, 어디요?
- 바로 여기 터진 곳이 있어요
- Where, where, where?
- There's a tear, right there.
이런, 이걸 봐요. 소매가 엉망이에요
완전히 비틀려 있잖아요
Ah, look at this, the sleeve
is all wrong. It's completely crooked.
- 아마 컨디션이 안 좋았나 보죠
- 아뇨. 그럴 리가 없어요
- Well, maybe she had a bad day.
- No, that's not possible.
난 8번 검사원을 알아요
I know inspector number 8.
그분은 어떤 결함도 놓치지 않아요
She never lets anything
get past her.
몽크 씨, 괜찮아요?
Mr. Monk, are you okay?
뭔가 잘못되었어요
Something's wrong.
8번 검사원한테 뭔가
몹시 나쁜 일이 생겼어요
Something is very wrong
with inspector number 8.
데니스
Dennis.
모델 살해범에게 종신형 선고
Life Sentence for Model's Slayer
MONK Season 4. Epi.10
Monk Goes to a Fashion Show
MONK Season 4 Epi. 10
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
진현경(jhk8012@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
박도현(naomiwatts@nate.com)
번역수정
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/01/13
해먼드 씨, 그 부분을
다시 들어 봅시다. 앉으세요
Mrs. Hammond, I need to
hear this again. Please.
집에 도착한 다음
You came home
남편이 쓰러져 있는 걸 발견한 게
한 시간쯤 전이라고요? / 네
and you found your husband on
the floor about an hour ago. / Yes.
- 부군은 칼에 찔려 있었고요?
- 네
- And he'd been stabbed?
- Yes.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
- 웃을 일이 아니에요
- 미안해요
- It's not funny.
- Sorry.
8번 검사원은
나한테 아주 중요해요
Inspector number 8
is very important to me
왜냐하면 아무리 나쁜 일이 생겨도
because no matter how
bad things go,
그분은 언제나 믿을 수 있는
분이라고 여겼거든요
I knew I could always count on her.
지금 생면부지의 사람에 대해
말하고 있다는 거 아시죠?
Mr. Monk, you understand you're talking
about someone you have never even met.
어딘지도 모를 공장에서
셔츠 품질 검사를 하는 분을요
Who works in a factory
somewhere who inspects shirts.
그분은 내 영혼의 반려자예요
She's my soulmate.
여자인지 남자인지도 모르잖아요
You don't even know if
it's a man or a woman.
난 그분을 사랑해요
I love her.
그분한테 문제가 생긴 것 같아요
I think she's in trouble.
맞아요. 퇴직했을지도 모르죠
어쩌면 새로 온 8번인지도 몰라요
Okay, maybe she's retired.
Maybe there's a new number 8.
그건 불가능해요
그분은 퇴직하지 않아요
It's not possible.
She would never retire.
자신의 일을 사랑하는걸요
이 셔츠를 보세요
She loves her work.
Look at this shirt.
5번 검사원이 퇴직한다면
이해가 돼요
Now, inspector number 5,
I can see him retiring,
그 사람은 몇 년 전부터
품질엔 신경도 안 썼으니까요
because he stopped caring
years ago.
- 몽크 씨
- 왜?
- Monk.
- What?
시체를 막 가져가려고 하거든요
They're about to take
the body away.
- 와서 보시겠어요?
- 곧 갈게
- You wanna come have a look?
- I'll be right there.
셔츠가 딱 5장 남았어요
I've only got 5 shirts left.
뭐... 뭔가를 쏟으면 어쩌죠?
만약 하나가 찢어지면?
What... what if I spill something?
What if one rips?
- 멸종 위기의 셔츠가 되면 어쩌죠?
- 셔츠에 집착하고 있습니다
- ...endangered species.
- He's obsessing over shirts.
- 셔츠들을 건조기에 넣으세요
- 네
- Put your shirts in the dryer.
- Yeah.
문을 닫고...
Close the door.
셔츠들이 교미를 하는지 잘 보세요
See if they mate.
- 이봐, 몽크
- 왜요?
- Hey, Monk.
- What?
- 어떻게 생각하나?
- 뭘요?
- What do you think?
- About what?
부엌에 있는 죽은 남자 말일세
Well, the dead guy in the kitchen.
죄송해요. 딴생각을 좀 하느라고요
Sorry. I was thinking
about something else.
셔츠를 검사하는 여자 분에 대해서
걱정하고 있었어요
He's worried about the woman
who inspects his shirts.
상점을 세 군데나 갔는데
I've been to 3 different stores.
경감님, 바느질이...
모두 잘못됐더라고요
Captain, the stitching,
it's..it was all wrong.
칼라는 비틀려 있고요
The collars are crooked.
경감님, 그냥 설명해 주세요
Okay, captain, just please
fill us in.
좋아요. 둘 다 클래식 음악가네
Okay, they're both
classical musicians.
- 둘은 약 6개월 전에 결혼했어
- 그냥 그분답지 않아서 그래요
- They got married about 6 months ago.
- It's just not like her.
부인은 스튜디오에서
첼로 연습을 하다가
The wife was down at
the rehearsal studio practicing her cello.
3시 30분에 집에 와서는
She comes home 3:30,
남편이 부엌 바닥에
죽어 있는 걸 발견했네
she finds her husband dead
on the kitchen floor.
사체엔 온기가 없었고
칼에 세 번 찔렸어
Room temperature,
stabbed 3 times.
거짓말하고 있어요
She's lying.
연습하고 있었던 게 아니에요
She wasn't practicing.
저렇게 긴 치마를 입고
첼로를 연주할 순 없거든요
You can't play the cello
wearing a long skirt like that.
내가 뭘 하려는지 알아요?
You know what I'm gonna do?
난 8번 검사원을 찾을 거예요
그분을 찾아보겠어요
I'm gonna find inspector 8.
I'm gonna track her down.
셔츠 공장은 로커웨이에 있어요
여기서 2시간 거리죠
Shirt factory's in Rockaway.
That's two hours from here.
- 몽크 씨 말이 맞는 것 같아요
- 그래. 경찰서로 데려가게
- I think he's right.
- Yeah, take her downtown.
이봐, 몽크
고맙네
Hey, Monk.
Thank you.
뭘 말입니까?
For what?
- 자네가 사건을 해결했네
- 아, 네. 고맙긴요
- You solved the case.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
만약 그분한테 문제가 생겼다면
내가 도울 수 있을지도 몰라요
If she is in trouble,
maybe I can help her.
저기 4번 검사원은
수습생인가 봐요
That's number 4.
He's a hack.
10번 검사원을 6번처럼
보이게 하잖아요
He makes inspector number 10
look like inspector number 6.
안녕하세요, 6번
Hi. 6.
저기 있네요
There she is.
저기 있어요
저 사람이에요
There she is.
That's her.
저분이 8번이라고요
That's number 8.
- 데이트라도 신청할 거예요?
- 아뇨, 전 그냥...
- Well, are you gonna ask her out?
- No, I'm just...
긴장되네요
I'm nervous.
좋아요. 가요
가자고요
Okay, go on.
Go on.
실례합니다
8번이시죠?
Excuse me.
Number 8?
전 에이드리안 몽크고, 이쪽은
제 친구인 나탈리 티거입니다
I'm Adrian Monk.
This is my friend Natalie Teeger.
에이드리안 몽크?
같은 분이세요?
Adrian Monk?
The same?
오, 보관해 두셨네요
Oh, you saved it.
그게 제가 써 본 유일한 팬레터예요
That's the only fan letter
I ever wrote.
전 마리아 오르티즈예요
I am Maria Ortiz.
마리아
만나서 영광이고 기쁩니다
Maria.
It's an honor and a pleasure.
주머니에 검사표를 넣으시는 걸
보다니 정말 기쁩니다
It's so nice when you can put a face
with the little tag in the pocket.
아... 이걸 합격시키시려고요?
Uh oh, are you approving this?
여기 작은 얼룩이 있는데요
This has a little stain there.
그럴 줄 알았어요
I knew it.
내 생각이 맞았어요
뭔가 걱정거리가 있으시군요
I knew it.
You are upset about something.
마리아 씨, 몽크 씨가
정말 많이 걱정했어요
Maria, Mr. Monk has been
really worried about you.
제가 아니에요
제 아들 파블로 때문이에요
It's not me.
It's my son Pablo.
아, 이 사건 기억해요
클리오 밴스라는 모델이죠
Oh, I remember this case.
The model, Cleo Vans.
신문은 모두 틀렸어요
사람들도 전부 틀렸고요
The papers are wrong.
Everyone is wrong.
파블로는 착한 애예요
그 애는 무죄예요
Pablo is a good boy.
He's innocent.
이런... 힘드시겠군요
Oh, I know it's hard.
일에 집중하면 기분이
나아지실지도 몰라요
You might feel better if you
focused on your work.
그러니까... 이 셔츠들을
다시 검사하다 보면요
You know, and started
inspecting these shirts again.
문제가 있어요, 마리아 씨
Here's the thing, Maria.
- 저한테 셔츠가 딱 5장 남았거든요
- 몽크 씨, 몽크 씨
- I've only got 5 shirts left.
- Mr. Monk, Mr. Monk,
당신이 도우면 되잖아요
그래요
you can help her.
Yes.
마리아 씨, 몽크 씨는 탐정이거든요
Maria, Mr. Monk is a detective.
훌륭한 탐정이시죠
유명하세요
He's a great detective.
He's famous.
그럼 제 아들을 도와주시려고
여기 오신 건가요?
And you came here
to help my boy?
그게요...
Um, well,
아뇨. 사실 제 최우선 순위는...
no, actually my, ah...
마리아 씨를 다시 일에
집중하게 만드는 거거든요
my first priority really is
to get you to focus again.
왜냐하면...
셔츠 때문에요, 마리아
You know, because
the shirts, Maria...
몽크 씨, 선생님 같은 분이 절
도와주시기를 기도해 왔답니다
Mr. Monk, I have been praying
for such a one as you to help me.
파블로는 결백해요
Pablo is innocent.
그 애를 만나 보시면
알게 되실 거예요
When you talk to him,
you will see.
자... 잠깐요
그 애를 만나다뇨?
Whoa, whoa, when I talk
to him?
아뇨. 저... 저는
동의한 적 없는데요
No. I... I never agreed.
오, 세상에.. 마리아
너무 죄송해요
Oh my gosh, oh, Maria.
I'm so sorry, sweety.
그만해요
Stop it.
어떻게 이런 일이 생긴 거죠?
How did this happen?
어째서 이런 일을 하라는 거예요?
How do you talk me into these things?
- 왜냐하면 옳은 일이니까요
- 이거 읽어 봤어요?
Because it's the right thing to do.
Have you read this?
봐요. 증인들도 있고
DNA 증거도 있어요
Look, there are witnesses.
There's DNA evidence.
나탈리, 그 애가 범인이에요
의심의 여지가 없어요
Natalie, he did it.
There's no doubt about it.
글쎄요. 만나서 해될 것도 없잖아요
Well, it doesn't hurt to meet him.
마리아한테 돌아가서
아들이 유죄라고 말한다면
If I go back to Maria
and tell her that her son is guilty,
완전히 절망하게 될 텐데
그럼 상황이 더 나빠진다고요
she'll completely fall apart
which will be worse
- 셔츠가 5장밖에 안 남았으니까요
- 쉬!
- because I'm down to 5 shirts.
- Shh.
몽크 씨
Mr. Monk.
- 티거 씨?
- 네
- Ms. Teeger?
- Yes.
어머니랑 통화했어요
오신다는 말씀은 들었습니다
I talked to my mother.
She told me you were coming.
어떻게 제 어머니를 아시죠?
How do you know my mother?
네 어머니가 하시는 일로 알게 됐다
내가 어머니의 대단한 팬이거든
From her work at the factory.
I'm a big fan.
팬요?
A fan?
파블로, 당신 어머니께서
사건을 조사해 달라고 부탁했어요
Pablo, your mother asked
that we look into your case.
우린 당신 입장을 듣고 싶어요
We'd like to hear your side.
전 클리오 밴스를 죽이지 않았어요
그게 제 입장이에요
I did not kill Cleo Vans.
That is my side.
전 클리오를 만난 적도
본 적도 없다고요
I never met her.
I never see her.
아믹 호텔에서 패션쇼가 있었어요
There was a fashion show
at Amic Hotel.
전 심부름꾼이었는데
I was a deliver boy.
거기에 옷을 좀 배달한 다음
집으로 갔어요
I deliver some clothes there,
then I go home.
그리고 다음 날 저는 체포되었죠
And the next day, I'm arrested.
Eso es una pesadilla.
(That is a nightmare.)
이건 악몽이에요
It is a nightmare.
파블로, 네 DNA가
희생자의 온몸에 있었어
Pablo, your DNA was
all over the victim.
네 피와 머리카락...
Your blood, your hair.
그건 어떻게 설명할 거지?
How do you explain that?
저도 모르겠어요
I don't know.
그건 실수예요
It's a mistake.
아... 아니,
착오라는 게 옳겠죠?
A misunderstanding?
클리오 밴스의 룸메이트가
증언하기를...
Clea Vance had a roommate
who testified
클리오가 널 두려워했다고 하던데
that Cleo was afraid of you.
네가 클리오를
스토킹 했다고 말했더군
She said that you were
stalking her.
봐라
Look.
바로 여기 적혀 있어
It says right here.
파블로 오르티즈는
클리오에게 집착했다
Pablo Ortiz was obsessed with her.
보이니? 바로 여기 있잖니
You see that?
Right there.
보여요
I see it.
거짓말을 하는구나, 파블로
그렇게 쓰여 있지 않다
You're lying, Pablo.
It doesn't say that.
넌 영어를 못 읽어. 그렇지?
You can't read English,
can you?
예, 못 읽어요
No, sir.
전 아버지와 멕시코에서 자랐죠
I was raised in Mexico
with my father.
여기서는 3년간만 살았기 때문에
영어를 말할 수는 있지만...
I have been here 3 years only
and I can speak English
읽지는 못합니다
but I cannot read.
왜 그러세요?
What is it?
- 비상구예요
- 그런데요?
It's the emergency exit. / Yeah?
- 열지 마시오. 경보기 작동함 -
범인은 그걸 이용하지 않았어요
- "DO NOT OPEN. ALARM WILL SOUND." -
Well, the killer didn't use it.
즉, 이 평면도에 따르면
According to this floor plan,
범인은 주방을 통과해서
뒤로 돌아가야만 했다는 거죠
he would've had to go all
the way around back through the kitchen.
사람들도 많고 위험한 길로 말이에요
It was crowded, it was risky.
누가 자기를 목격할 수도 있잖아요
Somebody could've seen him.
그런데도 범인는 비상구를 이용하지
않았군요. 경보기가 울릴까 봐요
Yeah, but he wouldn't use it.
The alarm would sound.
바로 그거예요
Exactly.
누구든 이 여자를 죽인 사람은
그 표시를 읽었어요
Whoever killed this woman
read that sign.
하지만 파블로는 읽지를 못하죠
And Pablo can't read.
파블로가 결백하다고 생각해요?
Do you think he's innocent?
그렇군요. 맞죠?
You do, don't you?
그 죽은 모델 말씀이군요?
The dead model, right?
그 사건 기억합니다
바로 제가 담당했죠
I remember this case.
I did the work on this one myself.
새로운 증거가 있습니까?
Is there any new evidence?
아니. 몽크가 살인자의
어머니를 만났네
No, Monk met the killer's mother.
- 그분은 셔츠 검사원이세요
- 아들이 결백하다고 맹세하시던데요
- She's a shirt inspector.
- She swears he's innocent.
압니다. 그게 우리 일 중
가장 힘든 부분이죠
Oh, I know.
That's the hardest part of the job.
울며 간청하는 어머니들 말이에요
The mothers crying and pleading.
- 그런 건 그립지 않을 겁니다
- 자네 어디 가나?
- That's one thing I'm not gonna miss.
- Where are you going?
못 들으셨어요?
저 퇴직합니다
Didn't you hear?
I'm retiring.
금요일에 송별 파티가 있는데
오시려면 오세요
There's a party for me on Friday
if you wanna come.
잘됐네요. 물론 가야죠
Cool, absolutely, I'm there.
퇴직한다고?
자네 몇 살인데? / 46살요
You're retiring?
How old are you? / 46.
- 복권 당첨이라도 됐나?
- 아뇨. 부동산에 투자를 좀 했죠
- Did you win the lottery?
- No, I've been investing. Real esate.
경감님은 저축한 걸로 뭐 하세요?
What have you been doing
with your savings?
음... 먹는 데 쓰지
Uh, eating.
내 회계사와 상담을 해 봐야겠군
You know, I need to talk
to my accountant.
- 회계사가 있으세요?
- 아뇨
- What, you have an accountant?
- Nope.
회계사를 먼저 구한 다음
상담한다는 얘깁니다
Gonna have to get an accountant,
then I'm gonna talk to him.
사진이 뭔가 이상해요
There's something wrong
with this picture.
- 뭐가?
- 글쎄요...
What? / I don't know.
뭔가가...
Something...
- 이게 클리오의 신발인가요?
- 맞아요
- So, these are her shoes?
- That's right.
네. 이 피 보이시죠?
Yeah, you see this blood?
이 머리카락과 섬유들도
전부 파블로 오르티즈의 것이죠
And this hair and these fibers.
They all belonged to Pablo Ortiz.
의심의 여지가 없어요
It's a slam dunk.
그래. 빠져나갈 구멍이
보이지 않는군
Yeah, I don't see any wiggle room here.
맞습니다. 사람들은 거짓말을 하죠
We got it right, man.
People lie.
사람들은 항상 거짓말을 해요
하지만 DNA는...?
People lie all the time,
but DNA?
- 거짓말을 하는 법이 없죠
- 전...
- It never lies.
- I'm thinking...
어쩌면 파블로가 범인이
아닐지도 모른다고 생각해요
I'm thinking maybe he's not the guy.
여기 비상구가 있거든요
You see, there's this exit door.
- 나도 비상구 얘긴 들었어요
- 바로 거기요
- Look, I heard about the exit door.
- Right there.
몽크, 나도 자넬 돕고 싶지만
Look, Monk, I'd follow you anywhere,
당장 처리할 사건이
4건이나 있네
but I've got 4 cases on my plate
right now.
하지만 열심히 해 보게
되든 안 되든 잘해 봐
But you have fun.
Knock yourself out.
고맙네, 고르도
Thank you, Gordo.
파티에서 뵙죠
See you at the party.
여기 나타샤 조렐의 진술이 있어요
Here's the statement from
that Natasia Zorel.
희생자의 룸메이트였죠
나타샤부터 시작합시다
She was the victim's roommate.
Let's start with her.
방금 나타샤 조렐한테
가신다고 하셨어요?
Did you just say you were
gonna go and talk to Natasia Zorel?
슈퍼모델이네
The supermodel.
그 사람이 나타샤야?
Is that her?
저기 말이죠... 사실 저는
지금부터 비번이거든요
You know, actually, I've got
the rest of the day off.
저도 같이 가는 게 좋겠어요
I should probably go with
you guys.
나도 같이 가겠네
뭘 위해서냐면...
You know, I think I'll come
along too. In the interest of ...
정의요?
Justice?
그래요, 정의
Yeah, justice.
너무 불행해 보여요
They look so unhappy.
어떻게 저렇게 매력적이면서도
슬퍼 보일 수 있죠?
How can they be that attractive
and be so sad?
글쎄요. 아마 사람들이
자신들을 좋아하고 있는지
Well, maybe it's because
we're never really sure
스스로는 결코 알 수
없기 때문이 아닐까요
if people like us for ourselves.
아냐, 이게 뭐야?
아냐, 아냐
No, what's this?
No, no, no.
내가 요구한 건
그게 아니야. 봐
That's not what I asked for.
Look.
칼라가 이렇게 벌어져야 해
알았어?
The collar has to flare like this.
Do you see?
줄리안, 그거 막 칠한 건데요
Julian, they just painted that.
발정 난 암컷이라고
생각하란 말이야
She's an animal.
She's in heat. Good.
거기! 어떻게 생각해요?
You.
What do you think?
마음에 듭니다
I like it.
마음에 든다?
You like it?
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
What's that supposed to mean?
좋아하거나 아니면 싫어하느냐죠
Say you love it or say you hate it.
어중간한 건 의미가 없어요
Anything in between is pointless.
물수건, 물수건, 물수건
Wet one, wet one, wet one.
빨리 줘. 고맙네
Come on.
Thank you.
거기! 푸른 셔츠
You, blue shirt.
- 여기 오디션 보러 왔소?
- 저요?
- Are you here to audition?
- Me?
- 아뇨
- 한번 생각해 보는 게 어때요?
No. / You may want consider it.
자세가 마음에 드는데
I like your attitude.
안녕하세요
Hello.
만일 날 강탈하려거든
총을 가져와야 할 겁니다
If you're gonna rob me,
you should bring a gun.
뭐라고요?
Pardon me?
그 블라우스 말이에요
The blouse.
내 디자인의 복제품이에요
It's a knock-off of one of my designs.
그래요? 몰랐어요
Oh, it is?
I didn't know.
물론 몰랐겠죠
뭐 그거야 범죄는 아니지
Of course, that's not the real crime.
진짜 범죄는 그걸 입고도
맵시가 안 난다는 거지 / 줄리안
- The real crime is how you look in it.
- Julian.
쇼 다음 날에 이만 화장품과
약속을 잡았어요
We booked Iman the day
after the show.
그리고 모델들이 도착했어요
새 얼굴이 필요하다고 하셔서요
And the girls are here. You said
you wanted some fresh faces.
- 좋아, 좋아
- 저 사람이 범인이에요
- Good, good.
- He did it.
나탈리, 저 사람은 용의자도
아니에요 / 빌어먹을
Natalie, he's not even
a suspect. / Damn.
아니, 돌아봐
No, turn around.
이번엔 안 되겠군
다음 기회에 오지
Not this time.
Next time. Ah.
그래, 그래. 완벽해
Yes, yes, you're perfect.
- 이름이 뭐지?
- 새라예요
- What's your name?
- Sarah.
새라
Sarah.
천국이 천사 하나를
잃어버린 게 틀림없군
Heaven must be missing
one of its angels.
실례해요
미안합니다
Excuse me.
Sorry.
뭐요?
What?
저, 별건 아니고요...
Well, it's nothing.
It's just..
눈썹 한쪽이 그다지
좋아 보이지 않아서요
One of those eyebrows aren't
gonna look so good.
어느 쪽?
Which one?
오른쪽보다 왼쪽이 더 높아요
Well, the left one's higher
than the right one.
이쪽 눈썹이 저쪽보다 약간 낮군
This eyebrow is a little
bit lower than that one.
다음 기회에 봅시다, 새라
Maybe next time, Sarah.
Yeah.
참여해 줘서 고마워요
Thanks for coming in.
- 누구세요?
- 에이드리안 몽크입니다
- Who are you?
- I'm Adrian Monk.
샌프란시스코 경찰과
함께 일하고 있습니다
I'm with the San Francisco Police.
그래요. 우린 나타샤 조렐을
만나러 왔습니다
Yeah, we're here looking for
Natasia Zorel.
나타샤는 일하고 있어요
Well, she's working.
아, 부탁 하나만 합시다
Oh, and do me a favor.
쇼가 끝나기 전에는 나타샤를
체포하지 말아 주세요
Don't arrest her until after
the show.
나타샤는 아무 짓도 안 했습니다
She hasn't done anything.
저흰 클리오 밴스 살인 사건
조사차 온 겁니다
We're actually here looking
into the murder of Cleo Vans.
왜요?
다 끝난 일 아닙니까?
Why?
Isn't that old news?
범인은 감옥에 있는 줄 알았는데요
I thought the killer was
in jail somewhere.
당신들은 신문도
안 읽습니까?
I mean, don't you people
read the newspapers?
클리오와 아는 사이셨습니까?
Did you know her?
난 캘리포니아에 있는 모델과
모델 지망생들을 다 압니다
I know every model in California
and every wannabe.
클리오는 모델이 되어서는 안 됐어요
Cleo was a should-not-have-been.
지난번 쇼에 술에 취한 채
나타났단 말입니다
You know, she showed up wasted
to my last show.
쇼를 거의 망칠 뻔했죠
Almost ruined me.
여러분도 명심하도록 해요
Now let that be a lesson
to you girls.
클리오가 지난번 쇼를
망치고 나서 2시간 후에
She ruined my last show
and two hours later,
배달부가 클리오를 죽였어
농담 아니야
the delivery boy killed her.
And I kid you not.
그래도 나타샤를 좀
만나 보고 싶은데요
We'd still like to talk
to Natasia.
나타샤는 해변에 있어요
She's at the beach.
새 카탈로그를 찍고 있는 중이죠
We're shooting our new catalogue.
곧 그리로 가 봐야 하는데
Listen, I've gotta be there
very soon.
원한다면 함께 가시죠
So you can follow me
if you'd like.
좋아요, 여러분. 좋아
All right, girls, good.
그럼 거기서 만나요
난 줄리를 데리러 가야 하거든요
All right, I'll meet you there.
I gotta go pick up Julie.
옷도 갈아입고요
And change.
좋아, 그거야
바로 그 표정이야
Okay, that's it.
That's what I need.
계속해
포즈
Keep it going.
Sell it.
포즈
좋아, 다시
Sell it.
There we go, again.
좋아, 포즈
포즈
Good, sell it.
Sell it.
줄리
Sweetie.
여기 그대로 있어. 알았지?
엄마 갔다 올게
Stay right here, okay?
I'll be back.
뭐 해요?
What are you doing?
뭐라고요?
What?
서 있잖아요
I'm standing.
전 원래 이런 자세로 서 있어요
This is how I stand.
뭘 입고 있는 거예요?
What are you wearing?
옷이죠
전 원래 이렇게 입어요
Clothes.
This is how I dress.
- 전 원래 이렇게 서요
- 저도 원래 이렇게 입어요
- This is how I stand.
- This is how I dress.
미안하지만 끌 수 없나?
성가시구먼
Excuse me, would you
put that out? It's bothering me.
선생님도 피우고 계시잖아요
But you're smoking.
내가 피우는 건 괜찮아
My smoke isn't bothering me.
고맙네
Thank you.
좋아요. 나타샤를 만나 보세요
대신 빨리 끝내세요
All right. She'll talk to you.
But make it quick.
잡담이나 하라고 시간당 천 달러나
모델료를 지불하는 게 아니니까
I'm not paying her 1000 dollars
an hour just to chat.
수고했네
잠깐 실례 좀 할까?
Thank you.
Can you give us a minute?
물론이죠
좋아요, 여러분. 10분간 휴식
Sure.
All right, everybody, take 10.
- 나타샤한테 다른 드레스를 입히세요
- 우리 예쁜이...
Let's get her in the other
dress, please. / Sweetheart.
아주 아름다워
You look ravishing.
이 신사 분들은 경찰서에서 오셨는데
These gentlemen are from
the police department.
클리오 밴스에 대해
얘기하고 싶어 하셔
They want to talk to you
about Cleo Vans.
- 왜요?
- 글쎄요...
- Why?
- We're not sure.
- 풍차를 향해 돌진하는 거라고 해 두죠
- 풍차요?
(가상의 범인을 찾고 있다는 뜻)
- Probably just tilting at windmills.
- Windmills?
책에서 문학적 인용을 하는 거야
(소설 '돈키호테'에서 인용)
It's a literary reference.
From a book.
그럼 제가 옷 갈아입는 동안
얘기하시면 되겠군요
Um, I guess we can talk
while I change.
저쪽으로 오시겠어요?
Meet me over there?
한 분만요
Only one of you.
좋아요
Okay.
알파벳순으로 하는 게 유일하게
공정한 방법인 것 같네요
Guess the only fair way
is alphabetically.
- 에이드리안
- 아뇨, 성으로요
Adrian. / No, last names.
그러니, A는 없고
So, A is no..
B도 없고, C도 없고
D는 디셔, 바로...
B, no. C, no.
D, Disher, that's...
몽크, 자네가 가게
자네 사건이잖나
Monk, you go.
It's your case.
디셔가 몽크 전에 오는데요
그게 제일 빠른 성이라고요
Disher comes before Monk.
It's the first last name.
뭡니까? 상복(喪服)이라도
차려입은 거요?
What are you, in mourning
for your life?
당신은 클리오의 룸메이트였죠?
You were Cleo's roommate?
- 네. 제일 친한 친구였고요
- 그렇군요
- Yeah, and best friend.
- I see.
알았어요
I see.
Whoa, whoa.
괜찮아요
전 안 부끄러운걸요
It's okay.
I'm not shy.
당신
You have..
당신 어깨에 뭔가 묻었네요
You have something on
your shoulder.
아, 그거 점이에요
제 트레이드 마크죠
Oh, it's a mole.
It's my trademark.
파블로 오르티즈와
아는 사이셨나요?
Yeah, did you know Pablo Ortiz?
아는 사이는 아니었지만
I didn't know him.
클리오가 파블로를
무서워했다는 건 알아요
Except that Cleo was terrified of him.
- 클리오를 스토킹 했거든요
- 네
- He was stalking her.
- Yes.
하지만 증거는 없던데요
There's no evidence of that.
전화 통화 기록도 없고
다른 점도 없고
No phonecalls.
No other moles.
아니... 증인들요
다른 증인들이 없었어요
I mean witnesses.
No other witnesses.
제가 지어낸 얘기란 말씀인가요?
Are you saying I made it all up?
- 그게...
- 제가 왜 그러겠어요?
Um... / Why would I do that?
모르겠습니다
I don't know.
제가 분명히 봤어요
Look, I saw what I saw.
파블로가 꽃을 주며
수작을 걸었다고요
He brought her flowers.
He hit on her.
이미 일 년 전에 다
증언한 내용이에요
I already testified about all this
a year ago.
나도 당신 진술서를 읽었어요
I read your statement.
그럼 다시 읽으세요
Then read it again.
뭐 하세요?
What are you doing?
이쪽에 하나를 그려 넣으면
If you put one on this side,
그러니까...
완벽할 거예요
you know, you'd be perfect.
당신 출세길도...
Your career would..
질문 더 있으세요?
Do you have any more questions?
- 아뇨
- 잘됐네요
No. / Good.
일하러 돌아가야 하거든요
Cuz I gotta get back to work.
- 안녕하세요
- Hey.
- Hi, there.
어떻게 됐나?
How'd it go?
섹시하네요
She's hot.
약간 화가 난 상태예요
She's mildly irritated.
잠시 진정할 시간을 주자고요
Give her a minute, she'll calm down.
좋아, 대단해
아름다워
All right, great.
You're beautiful.
- 저 왔어요
- 줄리
Hi. / Sweetie.
엄마, 나 지루해요
Mom, I got bored.
여기 있으면 안 돼요?
조용히 있을게요
Please, can I stay?
I won't say anything.
아름다워. 대단해
Beautiful, great.
대단해. 최고야
Great, awesome.
엄마, 저 사람이 절 보는데요
Mom, that man's looking at me.
- 뭐 하는 걸까요?
- 글쎄다
- What's he doing?
- I don't know.
- 하지 씨
- 쉬!
Mr. Hodge. / Sshh.
누구예요?
너 누구니?
Who is she?
Who are you?
제 딸 줄리예요
이쪽은 하지 씨야
This is my daughter, Julie.
This is Mr. Hodge.
- 걷는 걸 보자꾸나
- 왜요?
- Let me see you walk.
- Why?
번개가 칠지도 모른다
네 인생이 바뀔지도 모른단 뜻이다
Because lightning may be striking.
Your life may be changing.
자, 그냥 저기로 걸어가 봐
Now, just walk over there.
어서
Come on.
그렇지
좋아
That's it.
Good.
돌아봐
Turn around.
머리를 들고 웃어
돌아와
Hold your head up, smile.
Come back.
좋아
Good.
날 위해 모델을 해 주면 좋겠구나
I want you to model for me.
목요일 밤 쇼에 출연시켜 주마
You can be in the show
on Thursday night.
넌 대단한 스타가 될 수 있어
You know, you could be
a big star.
아주 멋지고 신나는 일이지
Great and wonderful things.
- 세상에
- 안 돼요. 얘는 13살이에요
- Oh, my god.
- No, she's 13 years old.
더 어린 모델들도 있어요
I've had models younger than that.
13살이면 사실상
중년이나 다름없죠
13, she's practically middle aged.
감사합니다만 안 되겠어요
Thank you, I don't think so.
어쨌든 당신이 결정할
문제는 아닙니다
Anyway, it's not up to you.
이건 줄리와
줄리 친엄마 사이의 문제니까요
This is between Julie and
her biological mother.
제가 줄리의 친엄마예요
I am her biological mother.
Oh.
엄마 / 안 돼
Mom. / No.
줄리, 내려와
음식 식겠다
Sweetie, come on.
It's gonna get cold.
너 화장했니? 18살이 되기 전까지
모델 일은 안 된다고 했다
Are you wearing makeup?
I told you, not until you're 18.
엄마, 18살까지 기다렸다간
너무 늦을 거예요
Mom, when I'm 18,
it'll be too late.
저 정말 하고 싶어요
I really wanna do this.
모델 일을 하는 여자들이
얼마나 문제가 많은지 아니?
You know, a lot of these girls
have serious problems, okay?
약물 중독에 거식증 같은 거 말이야
Drugs and eating disorders.
딱 한 번만요
It's just one show.
만약 엄마 말씀이 옳고
저도 별로면 그만둘게요
And if you're right and
I hate it, I'll quit.
하지만 적어도 시도는 해 볼래요
But at least I'll try it.
엄마도 제게 항상 새로운 걸
시도하라고 하셨잖아요
You always told me to
try new things.
모델 일보다는
변호사가 더 어울리겠다
Just forget modeling,
you should be a lawyer.
해도 된다는 말씀이죠?
Is that a yes?
대신 엄마가 항상
네 옆에 있을 거야
I'm gonna be with you
the whole time.
우와, 줄리안 하지의 모델이 되다니
Wow, modeling for Julian Hodge.
그분 멋지지 않아요?
Isn't he wonderful?
내가 쓰던 표현과는
좀 다르긴 하구나
It's not exactly the word
I would've used.
줄리안
Julian.
안녕
Hi.
놀랐나?
You surprised?
아까 일로 짐작은 했어요
Not after today.
깜짝 놀라셨을 거라 생각했거든요
Thought you might be
freaking out.
그 사람들이 뭔가 알아냈나요?
Do they know anything?
아닐 거야
I don't think so.
담배는 안 피우시네요
You're not smoking.
안 피워
No, no.
담배는 나쁜 냄새를
남기는 경향이 있잖아
You know, cigarettes,
they tend to leave a nasty odor.
내가 여기 있었다는 걸 알리고
싶지도 않고 / 누구에게요?
I wouldn't want them to know
I was here. / Who?
경찰들 말이야
The police.
경찰들한텐 아무 얘기도 안 했어요
Oh, I didn't tell them anything.
하지만 하게 될 거야
But you will.
결국에는
Eventually.
하지만... / 쉬!
But... / Sshh.
그게 네 탓은 아니지
It's not your fault, my darling.
넌 너무 예쁘니까...
You're just too pretty.
그리고 너처럼
예쁜 얼굴을 가진 미인은
And beauty like yours,
a face like this..
쉬...
Sshh.
그런 압박을 견뎌 내지 못할 거야
You just wouldn't be able
to take the pressure.
어떻게 보이나, 고르도?
How does it look, Gordo?
자살처럼 보이고
자살 냄새가 나는데요
It looks suicide.
Smells like suicide.
저는 자살 쪽에 돈을 걸겠어요
My money's on suicide.
물을 두 병이나 비웠어요
한 30알쯤 먹은 것 같아요
She drained two of those
bottles and maybe 30 sleeping pills.
- 처방전은 있던가?
- 아마도 아닐걸요
- Were those prescription?
- Probably not.
담당의에게 확인해야겠군
적어 두게
We'll check with her doctor.
Make a note.
기억하겠습니다
I'll remember.
수첩은 어디 있나?
Where's your notebook?
안 가져왔어요
I didn't bring it.
이태리 옷이거든요
수첩을 넣으면 맵시를 망칩니다
It's an Italian suit.
It was ruining the lines.
걱정 마세요
알아들었어요
Don't worry.
I got it.
방해되나요?
Am I in your way?
아마 당신과 말하고 난 후에
우울해졌나 봐요
She probably got depressed
after you spoke to her.
살인과 관련된 기억들이
전부 되살아났겠죠
All those memories about
the murder bubbling up.
난 그렇게 생각 안 해요
컵에 지문이 찍혀 있잖아요
I don't think so. There's one set of
fingerprints on the glass.
그래요. 피해자의 지문이죠
Yeah, they're hers.
하지만 보세요. 나타샤는
립스틱을 바르고 있는데
But look, she's wearing lipstick.
컵에는 립스틱이 묻지 않았어요
There's no lipstick on the glass.
누군가 컵을 닦아 냈어요
Somebody wiped down the glass
그러고 나서 나타샤의 손에
다시 쥐여 놓은 겁니다
and then put it back in her hand.
좋아
Okay.
지금부터 살인 사건 수사로 전환한다
This is now a homicide investigation.
출입을 제한하고
아무것도 건드리지 말도록
Lock this joint down.
Nobody touches anything.
멋쟁이, 가서 수첩 빌려 와
Fabio, go and borrow a notebook,
연필도 빌리고
탐문 수사 시작해
and borrow a pencil and start
talking to neighbors.
경감님, 그게 무슨 뜻인가요?
Captain, what do you think
it means?
누군가 몽크 때문에
겁을 먹었다는 뜻이죠
It means that your boss
scared somebody.
편히 쉬기를
Rest in peace.
신사 숙녀 여러분
10분 후 리허설을 시작합니다
Ladies and gentlemen,
rehearsal's up in 10 minutes.
자기 위치에 서 주십시오
최종 점검입니다
Please take your places.
Final touches.
정말 예쁘죠?
She looks beautiful, doesn't she?
너무 예뻐요
Too beautiful.
가끔은 줄리 얼굴 여기에 털 박힌
사마귀가 있었으면 좋겠다니까요
Sometimes I wish she had
big old fat hairy wart right here.
아뇨. 여기가 더 나을 거예요
No, maybe in here.
여러분, 이쪽으로
잠시만 모여 주시겠습니까?
Everyone, could you just come
around here for a moment, please?
고마워요
Thank you.
좋아요. 그거 내려놓고요
됐어요
Yes, put that down.
That's okay.
그건 나중에 하세요
고마워요
Do that later.
Thank you.
그냥 몇 마디 짧게 하고 싶어서요
I just want to say a few quick words.
오늘은 우리에게 끔찍한 날이었죠
This has been a terrible
day for us today.
왜냐하면 아시다시피 어젯밤
우리의 절친한 친구를 잃었으니까요
Because as you know, last night
we lost a dear dear friend.
전 여기 계신 여러분 모두가
And I know all of you here,
everyone,
나타샤를 얼마나 사랑했는지
잘 알고 있습니다
how much we loved Natasia.
물론 나타샤가 우릴
미치게 했을 때는 빼고요
Except of course, when she was
driving us nuts.
난 나타샤가 여기 있는 걸
느낄 수 있어요
I can feel her here.
그녀의 정신과 영혼이 느껴집니다
여러분도 느껴지나요?
I can feel her spirit, her soul.
Can you feel that?
내일 밤 쇼에서도 우리와 함께
있어 줄 거라고 믿습니다
And I know she's going to be
with us tomorrow night at the show.
그러니 나타샤를
실망시키지 맙시다
So, let's not let her down.
좋아요
Good.
이건 널 위한 거야, 자기
This one's for you, baby.
좋아요
고마워요
Great.
Thank you.
컷, 컷!
Cut, cut!
컷, 컷, 컷!
Cut, cut, cut.
줄리, 줄리
Juie, Julie.
줄리, 뭐 잊은 거 없니?
Julie, have you forgot something?
뭘요? / 일에 관한 한 나는 완전히
괴물이라는 걸 잊었느냔 말이다
What? / Have you forgot that when
it comes to my art, I'm a total monster?
널 좀 보란 말이야
엉망이잖아
I mean, just look at yourself.
Look, you're a mess.
여길 봐라
이걸 보라고
I mean, look here.
Look at this.
칼라를 봐!
봐. 모두 꼬여 있잖아
Look at the collar.
Look, it's all twisted.
그리고 드레스의 이 주름 좀 봐라
And all these wrinkles
on the dress.
- 봐라, 얘야
- 나탈리
- I mean, look, sweetheart.
- Natalie.
- 사건 파일 가지고 있어요?
- 뭐요?
- Do you have the case file?
- What?
사건 파일요
좀 줘 봐요
The case file.
Give it to me.
뭐가 잘못됐는지 알았어요
봐요
I knew something was wrong.
Look.
이걸 봐요. 클리오의 몸은
완전히 뒤틀려 있지만
Look at this.
Her body, it's all contorted.
칼라와 버튼은 완전히 똑바르죠
The collar, and her buttons
are perfectly straight.
범인이 클리오를 죽인 후에
칼라와 버튼을 똑바로 한 거죠
After he killed her, he straightened
them out.
자신도 어쩔 수가 없었던 거죠
He couldn't help himself.
- 이 사람이 범인인 거예요
- 그 사람이 누군데요?
- He's the guy.
- Who's the guy?
줄리, 당장 가야 해
Julie.
We have to go right now.
왜요? / 지금은 말할 수 없어
여기서는 안 돼
Why? / I can't tell you now.
Not here.
- 하지만, 엄마
- 말대꾸하지 마!
- But, mom.
- Do not argue with me.
네 물건 당장 가져와
Get your stuff now.
이봐요, 뭐 하는...
Hey. What..?
무슨 일이에요?
What's going on?
줄리를 집으로 데려가는 겁니다
She's taking Julie home.
대체 왜 그러는 건데요?
Why on earth would she do that?
내가 나탈리한테 당신이 1년 전에
클리오 밴스를 죽였다고 말했거든요
Because I told her that you killed
Cleo Vans a year ago.
그리고 난 당신이 어젯밤
나타샤 조렐도 죽였다고 확신합니다
And I'm betting that you killed
Natasia Zorel last night.
당신 말고 누가 클리오 밴스의
옷을 똑바로 정리했겠어요?
Who else would have straightenend
the clothes on Cleo Vans's body?
왜 내가 그런 행동을 했겠습니까?
Oh, and why would I do
something like that?
- 나 역시 그랬을 테니까요
- 그게 답니까?
- I would have.
- Is that it?
옷매무새를 똑바르게 한다는 거?
Straightened out the clothes?
그건 증거가 아니오
그건 직감일 뿐이지
I mean, that's not evidence.
That's a hunch.
지금까지는 그게 답니다
That's all it is so far.
당신은 직감을 믿는군요. 그렇죠?
You trust your instincts, don't you?
그래요
Oh, yes.
그 재킷을 고를 때에도
And would it be the same
infallible instincts
지금처럼 확실하게
감이 오던가요?
that you used when
picked out that jacket?
그 단추들을 셔츠 끝까지 잠근 것도
직감에 따른 행동이고요?
Or when you did those buttons
right up to the top on your shirt.
증거는 어쩌고요, 몽크 씨?
당신도...
What about the evidence, Mr. Monk?
What about...
DNA에 대해서는 들어 봤겠죠?
Well, you've heard of DNA, right?
그걸 들으면 뭐 생각나는 거 없소?
I mean, does that ring a bell here?
- 네, 압니다
- 섬유, 머리카락, 혈액...
- DNA, yes.
- The fibers, the hair, and the blood,
그것들 모두가 감옥에 있는
파블로 오르티즈의 DNA였소
they all belong to that boy, Pablo Ortiz,
who's in jail.
내가 범인일 수는 없어요
It couldn't have been me.
절대 불가능한 얘기죠
Just not possible.
맞아요
You're right.
가능하지 않죠
It's not possible.
하지만 당신이 죽였어요
But you did it.
고르도
Gordo.
- 이렇게 빨리 와 줘서 고맙네
- 물론이죠. 무슨 일인데요?
- Thanks for getting here so fast.
- Sure, what's going on?
잘 들어 보게
Get a load of this.
자, 위층 무도회장에서
패션쇼가 열렸었죠
Okay, there was a fashion show
upstairs in the ball room.
기억해요. 작년이었죠
I remember, last year.
그리고 모델 중 하나가 아시다시피
취해서 나타났습니다
And one of the models as you know
showed up drunk.
- 클리오 밴스 말이군요
- 맞습니다
- Cleo Vans.
- Exactly.
줄리안 하지 씨에 따르면 너무 취해서
쇼를 망쳐 놓을 뻔했다더군요
So drunk, according to Julian Hodge,
that she almost ruined his show.
하지 씨는 화가 난 나머지
이곳까지 클리오를 따라온 것 같아요
He was furious.
I think he followed her down here.
둘은 다퉜고 하지 씨는
자제력을 잃었죠
They argued, he lost control.
그리고 바로 여기서
클리오를 때려죽였지
And he killed her.
He beat her to death right here.
줄리안 하지 씨가요?
증거는 어쩌고요?
Julian Hodge?
What about the evidence?
하지 씨가 심어 놓은 거죠
파블로에게 누명을 씌웠어요
He planted it.
He framed Pablo Ortiz.
그게 가능해요?
Is that possible?
어떻게 그 모든 증거를 심고
자기 흔적을 지워 버렸을까요?
How can he plant all that evidence and
clean up every trace of himself?
사실은, 놓친 게 있습니다
Actually, he didn't.
He missed something.
이걸 보세요 / 사건 전날
위생 점검이 있었네
Check this out. / See there was
a health inspection the day before.
구석에 파리 끈끈이를 걸어 두었지
They hung that fly taper
in the corner.
- 어떻게 우리가 그걸 놓쳤죠?
- 우리도 오늘 아침 막 발견했어요
- How did we miss it?
- We just found it this morning.
저 난방기 뒤에서요. 싸우는 동안
저 뒤에 떨어진 게 틀림없어요
Behind that radiator. It must've
fallen back there during the fight.
보세요. 머리카락 서너 개가
거기 붙어 있어요
And look, there's 3 or 4
hair stuck to it.
클리오 밴스는 긴 머리였으니까
클리오의 머리카락일 수는 없죠
And it can't be from Cleo Vans
because she had long hair.
진짜 살인자인
줄리안 하지의 것이 틀림없어요
They must belong to Julian Hodge,
the real killer.
이게 우리에게 필요한 증거죠
This is the proof we need.
- 얼마나 빨리 검사할 수 있겠나?
- 바로 하겠습니다
- How soon can you do a test on those?
- I'll get right on it.
- 잘하셨어요
- 고마워요
- Good work.
- Thanks.
줄리, 다 된 것 같은데
Honey, I think they're done.
이런, 좀 푹 익었는지도 모르겠다
Oh, maybe a little overdone.
줄리
Julie.
얘야?
Honey?
존 카를로란 이름은
없습니다. 아셨어요?
I don't have a John Carlo, okay?
몇 번을 말씀드려야 합니까?
How many times do I have
tell you?
명단에 없으시다고요
아시겠어요?
You're not on this list.
All right?
안녕히 가세요
고맙습니다
Good night.
Thank you.
안녕히 가세요
Good night.
수고하십니다
전 명단에 있어요
Hello.
I'm on the list.
- 성함요
- 퍼프 대디
- Name.
- Puff Daddy.
외(外) 1명요
이쪽은 제 여자 친구예요
Plus one.
This is my girl..friend.
- 안녕하세요
- 랩 가수 퍼프 대디라고요?
Hi. / Puff Daddy, the rapper?
아뇨. 그 퍼프 대디는 아니고요
Oh, no, not that Puff Daddy.
항상 이렇다니까요. 안 그래요?
This happens to me all the time,
doesn't it?
늘 그렇죠 / 네
All the time. / Yeah.
설명해 드릴게요
Let me explain.
어디서 시작해야 하나
네. 퍼프 대디가 둘인 거죠
Where to begin...
All right, there are 2 Puff Daddy's.
이름을 바꾸지 그러세요?
Why don't you change your name?
내가 퍼프 대디에게
하고 싶은 말도 바로 그겁니다
Why doesn't he change his name,
is what I'm saying.
내가 나이가 더 많거든요
그 이름은 내가 먼저 썼다고요
Cuz I'm older than him.
I had it first.
저번엔 어떤 변호사 말이
소송도 가능하다고...
One time, a lawyer told me
I could sue if I..
내 딸이 저 안에 있어요
난 들어갈 거예요
My daughter's in there.
I'm going in.
- 우린 들어가야 해요
- 이봐요!
- We gotta in there.
- Hey!
내 딸 보셨어요?
Have you seen my daughter?
내 딸 줄리 봤어요?
13살에 긴 금발이에요
Have you seen my daughter Julie?
She's 13, long blonde hair.
아름다워
Beautiful.
줄리는 적격이야
좋아, 아주 보기 좋아
Eligible Julie.
Good, she looks very good.
줄리
Julie.
나탈리, 음식은 먹지 말아요. 방금 모델
한 명이 저 뒤에서 토하는 걸 봤거든요
Natalie, don't eat the food. I just saw
one of the models back there throwing up.
- 줄리
- 올라가면 안 돼요
- Julie.
- You can't go up there.
저건 내 디자인이 아니야
사람들한테 알리도록 해
That's not my design.
Make an announcement.
어쩜 그런 식으로
나가 버릴 수가 있니?
You just can't run away
from me like that.
- 얼마나 놀랐는지 아니?
- 엄마, 제발, 엄마
- You scared me to death!
- Mom. Come on, mom.
우리 얘기 좀 하자. 알았지?
We need to talk about it.
All right?
- 난 우리가 말이 통한다고 생각했다
- 내려와!
- I thought we were partners.
- Get off.
엄마 때문에 정말 당황스러워요
Mommy, you're embarrassing me.
못하게 할 땐 이유라도 알려 주셔야죠
그러니 엄마랑은 말이 안 통한다는 거예요
You said I couldn't do this and
you don't even tell me why.
Which I can't partner you.
다 이유가 있어. 알겠니?
Well, I have my reasons, all right?
여기에서 벌어지고 있는
사건들 때문이야
There are grown up things
happening here.
위험한 사건이란다
There are dangerous things.
엄마를 믿어야 해, 아가
You have to trust me, honey.
- 죄송해요
- 나도 미안하다
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, too.
너 외출 금지야
You're so grounded.
들어 봐
Listen.
반드시 비평가들한테
술을 많이 먹이라고
Let's make sure that the critics
get lots to drink.
자, 밀라노에서 열릴
다음 쇼를 위해서
Well, look, here's to our next show
in Milan.
건배, 행운이 있기를
And chin chin, all the best.
그리고 축하해
잘했어
And congratulations.
Well done.
그 드레스를 입으니 눈이 부시네
You look stunning in that dress.
멋져
Fabulous.
대단한 쇼였어
It was a great show.
작은 사고 하나만 빼고 말이야
아주 터무니없었어
Except that one little incident.
It was ridiculous.
이런, 이 초라한 분은 누구시더라?
Oh, look what the cat dragged in.
당신은 거의 내 쇼를 망칠 뻔했어요
You know, you nearly ruined my show.
당신은 내 딸을 거의 망칠 뻔했고요
You nearly ruined my daughter.
하지 씨, 안녕하세요
Mr. Hodge, hello.
오, 안녕하세요
Oh, hello.
- 훌륭한 파티네요
- 감사합니다
- Great party.
- Thank you.
여기 당신에게 꼭 소개해 주고
싶은 사람이 있습니다
Here's somebody here I'd really
love for you to meet.
아, 저기 오네요
Oh, there he is.
- 자, 갑시다
- 뭡니까, 지금요?
- Oh. Come on.
- What, now?
- 물론이죠
- 좀 있다 보면 안 됩니까?
- Oh, yes.
- Can't it wait?
아뇨, 안 됩니다
아주 중요한 사람이거든요
No, no, no.
He's very important.
줄리안 하지 씨
하워드 고든 씨와 인사하시죠
Julian Hodge.
I'd like you to meet Howard Gordon.
하워드는 우리 과학 수사
전문가 중 하나죠
Howard is one of our
forensic experts.
오, 안녕하세요?
Oh, how do you do?
하워드는 클리오 밴스 사건에서
새로 발견한 증거를 검사하고 있었습니다
He's been examining some evidence
that we just uncovered
in the Cleo Vans case.
- 뭐라고요, 새 증거요?
- 맞습니다
- What, new evidence?
- That's right.
사람 머리카락 네 가닥을
범죄 현장에서 발견했어요
4 strands of human hair
found at the scene of the crime.
공식적으로 묻겠네, 고르도
이게 자네 보고서인가?
For the record, Gordo,
is this your report?
공식적으로, 맞습니다
For the record, yes, it is.
그리고 오늘 아침 우리가 발견한
이 머리카락을 자네가 분석했고?
And you examined these hair samples
that we found earlier today.
맞습니다
I did.
그럼 이 모발과 일치하는
사람이 있던가?
And were you able to match
these hairs to any individual?
- 네, 경감님
- 다시 공식적으로 묻지
- Yes, sir.
- And for the record,
누구의 머리카락이던가?
who did these hair belong to?
파블로 오르티즈입니다
Pablo Ortiz.
오르티즈? 그 꼬마는 살인죄로
이미 감옥에 있지 않습니까?
Ortiz, isn't that the boy
that's already in jail for the murder?
이런... 그럼 이만 마쳐도 되겠군요
Well, I think, gentlemen,
we're finished here.
파티로 돌아가도 되겠습니까?
Don't mind if I get back
to my party..
기다리세요
Hang on.
기다려요
고르도, 유감이네만
자네를 체포하겠네
Gordo, I'm sorry, but you're
under arrest.
살인 종범에 증거 위증죄로 말이야
Accessory to murder and
falsifying evidence.
- 뭐라고요?
- 내가 이해할 수 없는 게 있었죠
What? / Here's what I
couldn't figure out.
만약 당신이 유죄라면 어떻게
모든 증거들이 다른 곳을 지목할까?
If you were guilty, how could
all the evidence point somewhere else?
가능한 답은 하나뿐이었죠
There could be only one
possible answer.
증거가 잘못되었다는 거예요
There was something wrong
with the evidence.
우리가 뒷조사를 좀 했지, 고르도
We did some digging, Gordo.
올해 돈을 많이 벌었던데
부동산 덕은 아니더군
You did make a lot of money
this year, but it wasn't in real estate.
사실은 이렇게 된 거죠
Here's what happened.
클리오 밴스 살인 사건의
과학 수사를 했을 때
When you did the forensic work
on Cleo Vans's murder,
당신은 모든 증거가 줄리안 하지 씨를
지목하는 걸 알았죠
you realized all the evidence
pointed to Julian Hodge.
당신은 돈을 벌기로 결심했어요
You decided to cash in.
하지 씨 입장에서는 거절할 수 없는
제의를 한 거죠
You made Hodge an offer
he was in no position to refuse.
그 대가로 하지 씨에게
불리한 증거를 덮어 버렸어요
For a price, you'd bury the evidence
against him.
단 하나 문제가 있었죠
There was only one problem.
사건을 종결시켜야 했고
희생양이 필요했거든요
You had to close the case.
You needed a fall guy.
하지 씨는 영어만 간신히 할 줄 아는
파블로 오르티즈라는 이름의
Hodge remembered a young
delivery boy named Pablo Ortiz,
가난한 배달부 소년을 기억해 냈죠
a poor kid, barely spoke any English.
파블로는 완벽한 희생양이었어요
He was a perfect patsy.
하지 씨는 나타샤에게
자신을 돕도록 시켰어요
Hodge got Natasia to help him.
경찰에게 파블로가 자기 룸메이트를
스토킹 한다고 고발하도록 했죠
She called the police and
accused Ortiz of stalking her roommate.
경찰은 파블로를 체포했고
The police arrested Pablo.
모발과 혈액을 채취해서
당신에게 보냈어요
They took hair and blood
samples and sent them to you.
그 다음 일은 쉬웠어요
And the rest was easy.
라벨만 다시 붙이면
되는 일이었으니까요
All you had to do was relabel them.
파블로는 기회도 가져 보지 못했죠
Pablo never had a chance.
- 아무것도 증명할 수 없을걸요
- 그럴 필요도 없죠
- You can't prove any of this.
- We don't have to.
당신이 5분 전에 우릴 위해
증명해 줬으니까요
You proved it for us 5 minutes ago
이 모발이 파블로의 것이라고
당신 입으로 말했을 때요
when you swore that these hair
samples belonged to Pablo Oriz.
그럼 고르도 씨를 시험하기 위해
그 모발을 놓아두었다는 거요?
So you planted that hair
to test him.
말하자면... 그렇죠
Well, yeah.
- 그건 누구 모발이었어요?
- 제 거였어요
- Whose hair was it?
- It was mine.
나탈리가 족집게로 뽑았죠
그냥 확 잡아당기더군요
Natalie pulled it out with a tweezer.
She just yanked it out.
- 어떻게 했어야 하는 건데요?
- 그냥 잘라도 된다고 했잖아요
- What was I supposed to do?
- Could've cut them like I told you.
- 모낭이 필요했다고요
- 아뇨, 필요 없었어요
- We needed the follicles.
- No, we didn't need the follicles
왜냐하면 어떤 검사도
하지 않을 게 뻔했으니까요
because we knew he wasn't
going to test anything.
- 그게 전체 취지였어요
- 몽크 씨, 애처럼 굴지 말아요
- That was the whole point.
- Okay, don't be such a baby.
정말 당황스럽군요
가끔이라도 내 말을 경청해 주면 좋겠어요
It's embarrassing me.
If you had listened once in a while.
- 잠깐, 잠깐만!
- 듣고 있다고요
- Hang on. Hang on!
- I am listening.
뭘 하고 있었는지 잊어버렸잖나
I forgot what we were doing.
아, 그래. 당신들 둘을
체포하고 있었지
Oh, yeah, we're arresting you two.
절차는 아시죠, 고르도?
You know the drill, Gordo.
속담이 괜히 있는 게 아니군요?
So, it's true what they say, huh?
사람을 옷 입는 모양새로만
판단할 수는 없다는 얘기 말입니다
You can never judge a person
by how they dress.
있잖아요... 당신이 앞으로
입게 될 옷을 알려 드릴게요
Well, you know what, let me tell
you what you are gonna be wearing.
오렌지색을 좋아했으면 싶네요
약간 낙하산복 같은 건데요
I hope you like orange.
It's a little jumpsuit thing.
바로 여기 번호가 달려 있죠
Has a number right here.
어딜 가든 그걸 입을 거예요
감옥 안에서도, 운동장을 거닐 때도...
You can wear it anywhere really.
Indoors, walking around the yard.
내 아들!
Mi hijo.
감사합니다, 몽크 씨
Thank you, Mr. Monk.
어떻게 은혜를 갚아야 할까요, 몽크 씨
How can I repay you, Mr. Monk?
전 돈이 없거든요
I have no money.
그렇게 말씀하시니까 말인데요
지금 2시 반밖에 안 됐거든요
Now that you mention it,
it is only 2:30.
지금 출발하면 3시 15분까지는
공장에 돌아가실 수 있어요
If we left now, you could be
back at work at 3:15,
몇 시간 일하시면 셔츠 90벌이나
100벌 정도는 검사하실 수 있어요
put in a couple of hours,
inspect what, 90, maybe 100 shirts.
- 하지만 하루 휴가를 얻었는데요
- 아뇨, 아뇨
- But I took the day off.
- No, no, no.
그러고 싶지 않으시잖아요
You don't wanna do that, no.
당신은 8번 검사원이에요
You're inspector number 8.
많은 사람들이 당신한테
의지하고 있어요
You have a lot of people
depending on you.
몽크 씨, 저분들 분명
밀린 얘기가 많을 거예요
Monk, I'm sure they would like
to visit, you know, catch up.
네. 시간이야 많죠
주말 내내 얘기하면 되잖아요
Yeah, there's plenty of time.
A whole weekend for that.
Unless you wanna work on Saturday.
토요일에 일하고 싶지 않으시다면요
Puedes trabajar Saturday?
토요일에는 일하실 수 있어요?
Sabado, no?
Domingo?
토요일요. 안 돼요?
일요일은요?
Overtime.
초과 근무는요?
초과 근무 좋아하세요?
You like overtime?
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)